Mylynh Nguyen

Full Stack Web
Developer, Marketer
www.mylynhnguyen.com
https://github.com/nmylynh

CONTACT

Phone

+1(408)-205-2252

Email

contact@mylynhnguyen.com

Address

2391 Yesler Ct, San Jose, CA 95131

SKILLS

- React/Redux
- Python
- NodeJs, Express
- HTML/CSS
- Javascript
- Google Analytics
- SPSS / Qualtrics
- Jest/Supertest
- Django, SQLite3, Postgresql
- Languages: English, Vietnamese

EDUCATION

Lambda School

Full Stack Web Development

San Francisco State University

Bachelor of Science: Marketing

Evergreen Valley College

A.A.S: Health Sciences/ Allied Health

REFERENCES

Dzung

U.S. Best Transport Inc. (626) 493-4020 dzung@usbesttransport.com Vice President

Missy

PACE Learning Center (763) 443-8766 Manager

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Solution-driven professional with 5 years of business marketing and communications, and 3 years of full stack development. Excelling in highly collaborative work environments, with experience building responsive web applications across all platforms, meeting high standards for web design, user experience, best practices, usability, and speed–translating solutions into code.

EXPERIENCE

NuCamp, San Jose, CA

Instructor, March 2020 - Present

• Node instructor for the hybrid Full Stack Web Development program.

Pacific Data Integrators, San Francisco, CA, at PG&E

Full Stack Engineer, March 2020 - Present

- Developer for Sherlock, a CIO 100 Award winning innovative technology solution which assists and enhances the company's wildfire safety inspection efforts.
- Uses inspector mark-ups to train artificial intelligence algorithms which in turn are used to make the inspection process more efficient and effective
- Uses metadata to throughout the process to allow intuitive searchability of images

Edullo, Remote

Web Developer, Aug 2019 - Present

- Mapped out technological framework for app (e.g. React, Redux, Node.js)
- Mapped out database structure for algorithms being built in app
- · Researched implementations, such as Oauth, and socket.io
- Built CRUD operations for the Nodejs server, and designed migration tables and middle-ware for the application

SIXR, Remote

Web Developer Apprenticeship, July 2019 – September 2019

- Created a crowdfunding React/Redux application named Mympy Dreams under the VR company SIXR with a team of 7 developers
- Coded 90% of the RESTful API with NodeJS, express
- Created customized validation middleware to prevent invalid data
- Implemented third party APIs: auth0, Cloudinary, Stripe
- Wrote unit and integration tests for both front and backend
- Refactored the entire application (actions/reducers/components) to be scalable, readable, and performant

U.S. Best Transport Inc., Chicago, IL

Web Developer, Marketing and Communications, Sep 2015-Jan 2018

- Streamlined internal communications, increasing productivity rates by 33%
- Developed internal communications/logistics app: React/Redux, Node.JS
- Evaluated advertising strategies for compatibility with market segments
- Designed and created lead generation site: HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery
- Identified key market segments through Google Analytics
- Developed marketing campaigns through findings, increasing acquisition and conversion rates by 20%
- Strengthened the company's brand through the creation of their logo

PACE Learning Centers, San Francisco, CA

Head Academic Coach, Marketing Specialist, Aug 2013 - Oct 2015

- Developed multi-level consumer relation management strategies
- Planned and prepared customized curriculum for over 60 students
- Conducted marketing research using Qualtrics and SPSS
- Quantified qualitative data to analyze and identify key data points
- Identified correlations between variables of interest using regression
- Created innovative learning experiences based on regression analysis
- Supervised and trained personnel to become Academic Coaches